<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Anno regni gulielmi et Mariæ, regis &amp; reginæ Anglia, Scotia, Francia &amp; Hibernia quinto at the Parliament begun at Westminster the twentieth day of March, Anno Dom. 1689, in the second year of the reign of our sovereign Lord and Lady, William and Mary, by the grace of God, of England, Scotland, France and Ireland, King and Queen, defenders of the faith, &amp;c., and from thence continued by several prorogations and adjournments to the seventh day of November, 1693, being the fifth session of this present Parliament.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Laws, statutes, etc.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 110KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 36 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09016</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">61296978</idno>
  <idno type="VID">180540</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240860621</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E1037D</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R223329</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">61296978</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09016)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 180540)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2833:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Anno regni gulielmi et Mariæ, regis &amp; reginæ Anglia, Scotia, Francia &amp; Hibernia quinto at the Parliament begun at Westminster the twentieth day of March, Anno Dom. 1689, in the second year of the reign of our sovereign Lord and Lady, William and Mary, by the grace of God, of England, Scotland, France and Ireland, King and Queen, defenders of the faith, &amp;c., and from thence continued by several prorogations and adjournments to the seventh day of November, 1693, being the fifth session of this present Parliament.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Laws, statutes, etc.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary).</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>70 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by C. Bill and the executrix of T. Newcomb,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title taken from p. 3.</note>
                  <note>Text in black letter.</note>
                  <note>Title vignette: royal coat of arms.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Taxation --  Law and legislation --  England --  Sources.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1689-1702.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:180540:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:180540:1"/>
            <p>Anno Regni GULIELMI ET MARIAE, REGIS &amp; REGINAE <hi>Angliae, Scotiae, Franciae &amp; Hiberniae,</hi> QUINTO. At the Parliament begun at <hi>Westminster</hi> the Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth Day of <hi>March, Anno Dom.</hi> 1689. In the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Year of the Reign of our Sovereign Lord and Lady, <hi>WILLIAM</hi> and <hi>MARY,</hi> by the Grace of God, of <hi>England, Scotland, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> King and Queen, Defenders of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And from thence Continued by several Prorogations and Adjourn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments to the Seventh Day of <hi>November,</hi> 1693. being the Fifth Session of this present Parliament.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms of William and Mary</figDesc>
               <q>HO<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> SOIT QVI MAL Y PENSE</q>
               <q>DIEV ET MON DROIT</q>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>Charles Bill,</hi> and the Executrix of <hi>Thomas Newcomb,</hi> deceas'd, Printers to the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties. 1693.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="Act_of_Parliament">
            <pb facs="tcp:180540:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:180540:2"/>
            <head>Anno Quinto GULIELMI &amp; MARIAE. An Act for Granting to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sties an Aid of Four Shillings in the Pound for One year, for Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rying on a Vigorous War against <hi>France.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>E Your Majesties most Dutiful and Loyal Subjects the Commons Assembled in Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, acknowledging with all Humility and Thankfulness Your Majesties abundant care of Our Preservation; and being deeply sensible of that extraordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Charge and Expence with which Your Majesties Present Occasions are to be Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported, for the necessary Defence of Your Realms, and the Prosecution of a Vigo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous War against <hi>France,</hi> both by Sea and Land, have Chearfully and Vnanimously Given and Granted, and do hereby Give and
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:180540:3"/> Grant unto Your most Excellent Majesties, the Rates and Assessments herein after mentioned, to be Raised and Levied in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner following; and to most humbly beseech Your Majesties that it may be Enacted.</p>
            <p>And be it Enacted by the King and Queens most Excellent Majesties, by and with the Advice and Consent of the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons in this present Parliament Assembled, and by the Authority of the same, That Their Majesties shall Have and Receive the Rates and Assessments hereafter mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, of and from every Person Spiritual and Temporal, of what Estate or Degree soever he or they be; Which said Rates or Assessments, shall be Taxed, Assessed, Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vied and Paid into Their Majesties Receipt of Exchequer, according to the Tenor of this Act, and in manner and form following: That is to say, That all and every Person and Persons, Bodies Politick and Corporate, Guilds and Fraternities within this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> and Town of <hi>Berwick</hi> upon <hi>Tweed,</hi> having any E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>state in ready Monies, or in any Debts what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soever owing to them within this Realm or without; or having any Estate in Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, or other Chattels, or Personal Estate whatsoever within this Realm or without, belonging to, or in Trust for them (Except, and out of the Premisses deducted, such sums of Money as he or they do, <hi>bona fide,</hi> owe, and such Debts owing to them as shall be adjudged desperate by the Commissioners appointed by this Act; And
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:180540:3"/> also the Stock upon Lands, and such Goods as are used for houshold-stuff) shall yield, and pay unto Their Majesties Four shillings in the Pound, according to the true yearly value thereof for one year; (that is to say) For every Hundred Pounds of such ready Money and Debts; and for every Hundred Pounds worth of such Goods, Wares, Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandizes or other Chattels, or other Perso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Estate, the sum of Four and twenty Shillings; and so after that rate for every greater or lesser Sum or Quantity, to be As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sessed, Levied and Collected in manner here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after mentioned.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That all and every Person and Persons, Commissioner or Commissioners, having, using or exercising any Publick Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice or Employment of Profit (such Milita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Officers who are or shall be in Muster by the Muster Master General of the Army, or in Pay in Their Majesties Army or Navy, in respect of such Offices only excepted (other then Governours, Deputy or Lieutenant Governours of any Their Majesties Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>risons, Forts or Castles for their Salaries, or Pay for the same Governments) And al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so except such Persons in Their Majesties Ordnance whose Salaries do not exceed One hundred Pounds <hi>per Annum</hi>) and all and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very their Agents, Clerks, Secundaries, Substitutes and other Inferiour Ministers whatsoever, shall Yield and Pay unto Their Majesties the Sum of Four Shillings for every Twenty Shillings which he or they do
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:180540:4"/> receive in One Year, by virtue of any Sala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, Gratuity, Bounty-Money, Reward, Fees or Profits to him or them Accrewing, for or by reason or occasion of their several Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices or Employments, to be Assessed, Impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed, Levied and Collected, in such manner as hereafter is mentioned.</p>
            <p>And to the end a further Aid and Supply for Their Majesties Occasions may be Raised by a Charge upon all Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements and Hereditaments, with as much Equality and Indifference as is possible, by a Pound Rate of Four Shillings for every Twenty Shillings of the true Yearly Value for One Year and no longer, Be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That all and every Manors, Messuages, Lands and Tenements, as also all Quarries, Mines of Coal, Tin or Lead, Copper, Mundick-Iron, or other Mines, Iron Works, Salt Springs and Salt Works; All Allom Mines or Works, all Parks, Chases, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rens, Woods, Vnderwoods, Coppices; And all Fishings, Tythes, Tolls, Annuities and all other Yearly Profits; And all Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of what nature or kind soever they be, scituate, lying, and being, happening or arising within the Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> or Town of <hi>Berwick</hi> upon <hi>Tweed,</hi> or within any the Counties, Cities, Boroughs, Towns, Divisions, Ridings, Hundreds, Lathes, Wapentakes, Parishes and Places thereof, as well within Ancient Demesne and other Liberties and Privi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledged Places as without, shall be and are
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:180540:4"/> hereby Charged for One Year only and no longer, with the Sum of Four Shillings for every Twenty Shillings of the full Yearly Value, and so in Proportion for any greater or lesser Value; And all and every Person and Persons, Bodies Politick and Corporate, Guilds, Mysteries, Fraternities and Bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therhoods, whether Corporate or not Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate, having or holding any Manors, Mes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suages, Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments or other the Premisses, shall yield and pay unto Their Majesties the Sum of Four Shillings for every Twenty Shillings by the year, which the said Manors, Messuages, Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Hereditaments and other the Premis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses are now worth to the Leased, if the same were truly and <hi>bona fide</hi> Leased or Demised at a Rack Rent, and according to the full true yearly Value thereof, without any respect had to the present Rents reserved for the same, if such Rents have been reserved upon such Leases or Estates made, for which any Fine or Income hath been Paid or Secured, or have been lessened or abated upon consideration of Money laid out, or to be laid out in Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>provements, and without any respect had to any former Rates or Taxes there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon imposed, or making any abate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in respect of Reparations, Taxes, Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rish Duties, or any other Charges whatso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever; which said Sum of Four and twenty Shillings for the yearly Profit of every Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pounds Value of all Personal Estates, as aforesaid, and Four Shillings for every Twenty Shillings by the Year, of the said
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:180540:5"/> true yearly Value of all other the Premisses, shall be Assessed, Levied and Collected in manner hereafter mentioned, and shall be paid into the Receipt of Their Majesties Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer by Four Quarterly Payments: The First Payment thereof to be made upon the Six and twentieth Day of <hi>March,</hi> which shall be in the Year of our Lord One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand six hundred ninety and four.</p>
            <p>And whereas many of the Manors, Mes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suages, Lands, Tenements, Tythes, He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, and Premisses, intended by this Act to be charged with the Pound Rates, as aforesaid, stand incumbred with, or are subject and lyable to the payment of several Rent-charges or Annuities issuing out of the same, or to the payment of divers Feé-farm Rents, Rents Service or other Rents thereupon reserved or charged, by reason whereof the true Owners and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prietors of such Manors, Messuages, Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments and Premisses, do not in truth receive to their own use the true yearly value of the same, for which ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertheless, they are by this Act charged to pay the full Pound Rate of Four Shillings, for every Twenty Shillings of the true year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly value: It is therefore Declared and En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by the Authority aforesaid, That it shall, and may be lawful to, and for the Landlords, Owners, and Proprietors of such Manors, Messuages, Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Hereditaments and Premisses as are charged with the Pound Rate, as aforesaid, to abate and deduct, and to retain, and keép in his or their hands, Four Shillings in the
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:180540:5"/> Pound for every Feé-farm Rent, or other Annual Rent, or Payment Charged upon, or Issuing out of the Premisses, or any part thereof, or thereupon reserved; And all and every Person and Persons, who are, or shall be any way Intituled to such Rents, and Annual Payments, are hereby required to allow such Deductions and Payments, upon the receipt of the residue of such Moneys, as shall be due and payable to them for such Rents, or Annual payments reserved or charges, as aforesaid.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That for the better Assessing, Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering, Levying and Collecting of the several Sums of Money, so as aforesaid, Limited and Appointed to be paid; and for the more effectual putting of this present Act in Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution, all and every the Persons that were Named and Appointed Commissioners of, and for the Execution of the Act made in the Fourth year of Their Majesties Reign, Entituled, <hi>An Act for Granting to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sties an Aid of Four Shillings in the Pound for One year, for Carrying on a Vigorous War against <hi>France,</hi>
               </hi> and shall qualified according to the Directions of this Act, shall be Commissio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners for putting in Execution this Present Act, and the Powers therein contained, within all and every the several and respe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Counties, Ridings, Cities, Cinque Ports, Boroughs, Towns and Places for which they were Appointed Commissioners in the aforesaid Act.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That the said Commissioners,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:180540:6"/> so as aforesaid, Nominated and Appointed, shall (in the respective Counties, Ridings, Cities, Boroughs, Divisions, Towns and Places (for which they are Appointed Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners respectively) meet together at the most Vsual and Common Place of Meeting within each of the said Counties, Cities, Boroughs, Divisions, Towns and Places respectively, upon the Twentieth Day of <hi>Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bruary,</hi> which shall be in the Year of our Lord One thousand six hundred ninety and three; and the said Commissioners, or so ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of them as shall be present at the said First General Meeting, or the major Part of them, are hereby Authorized and Required to put this present Act in Execution, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the best of their Iudgments and Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretions, and shall then, if they shall see Cause, Subdivide and Distribute, as well themselves as other Commissioners then not present, for the Execution of this Act, into lesser Numbers, so as Three or more of the said Commissioners may be Appointed for the Service of each Hundred or other Divisi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and so as may best conduce to the Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rying on of Their Majesties Service hereby Required.</p>
            <p>And for the more effectual performance hereof, Be it Enacted and Declared by the Authority aforesaid, That the Commission<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers at their first General Meeting, or the major part of them present shall agree, and set down in Writing, who, and what num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of the said Commissioners shall act in each of the said Divisions or Hundreds, ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertheless not thereby to restrain the said
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:180540:6"/> Commissioners from acting as Commission<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers in any other part of the County or place for which they are nominated, and deliver a true Copy of such Writing to the Receiver General, to the end that there be no failure in any part of the due Execution of the Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice by this Act required.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That the said Commissioners shall direct their several or joynt Precept or Precepts, to such Inhabitants, High-Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stables, Petty-Constables, Bayliffs, and other like Officers and Ministers, and such number of them as they in their discretion shall think most convenient, requiring them to appear before the said Commissioners, at such place and time (not exceéding Ten days) as they shall appoint. And at such their Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearances, the said Commissioners shall openly read, or cause to be read unto them, the Rates and Assessments in this Act men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, and also openly declare the effect of their Charge to them, and how, and in what manner they ought and should make their Certificates, and how they ought to proceéd in the Execution of this Act, according to the Rates aforesaid. And if any High Consta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, Petty Constables, Bayliffs, Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants, or other Officers or Ministers to whom any Precept shall be directed, shall absent themselves without lawful excuse, to be made out by the Oaths of two credible Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses (which Oaths the Commissioners, or any two of them, are hereby Impowered to administer) or if any Person appearing, shall refuse to serve, then every such Person so ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:180540:7"/> default, or refusing to serve, shall for every time of such default or refusal, forfeit, and lose unto Their Majesties, such Sums as the Commissioners, or so many as shall be pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent, or the major part of them being present, shall think fit, not exceeding the Sum of Five Pounds, nor less then Fourty Shillings. And at and after such General Meeting had, and Charge given, as aforesaid, the said Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners shall take care that Warrants be Is<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sued forth and directed to Two at the least of the most able and sufficient Inhabitants of each Parish, Township or Place within the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective Divisions, thereby appointing and requiring them to be Assessors of all and every the Rates and Duties by this Act imposed; and shall therein also appoint and prefix a certain Day and Place for the said Assessors to appear before them, and to bring in their Certificates in Writing of the Names and Sirnames of every Person dwelling and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>siding within the limits of those places with which they shall be Charged, and of the Substance and Values of every of them in ready Money, Debts, Goods, Chattels or other Personal Estate whatsoever (except before excepted) or in Publick Offices or Imployments of Profit. And the said Assessors are therein also to be required, and are hereby injoyned to ascertain and inform themselves by all lawful ways and means they can, of the true and full yearly Value of all Manors, Messuages, Lands and Tenements, as also of all Quarries, Mines of Coal, Tin, or Lead, Copper, Mundick, or other Mines, Iron Works,
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:180540:7"/> Salt Springs and Salt-works, Allom Mines and Works, Parks, Chases, War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rens, Woods, Vnderwoods and Coppices; and all Fishings, Tyths, Tolls, Annui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, and other yearly Profits; And of all Hereditaments, of what nature or kind soever, scituate, lying and being, happening or arising within the Limits of those Places with which they shall be Charged; And be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing so thereof ascertained, they are to Assess all and every the said Manors, Messuages, Lands, Tenements and Premisses, before Appointed, to be Charged after the Rate of Four Shillings for every Twenty Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings, of the full yearly Value, as the same are Let for, or worth to be Let at the time of Assessing thereof, as aforesaid; And to bring with them, at the Time and Place, so as aforesaid, prefixed for their Appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance, a Certificate in Writing of the said Assessment; And shall then also return the Names of Two or more able and sufficient Persons, living within the Limits and Bounds of those Parishes, Townships, Constablewicks, or Places where they shall be Chargeable respectively, to be Collectors of the Moneys to be paid to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sties by this Act; For whose paying in to the Head Collector in manner hereafter mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, such Moneys as they shall be Charged withal, the Parish or Place wherein they are so Imployed shall be answerable. And if any Assessor, so as aforesaid, Appointed or to be Appointed, shall neglect or refuse to serve, or shall make default at the time ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed for his Appearance, (not having a
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:180540:8"/> Lawful Excuse to be Witnessed by the Oaths of Two credible Witnesses, which the said Commissioners, or any Two or more of them, have Power to Administer) or shall not perform his Duty, every such Assessor shall, for every such Neglect, Refusal or Default, forfeit and lose unto Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties such Sum as the Commissioners, or so many of them as shall be present, or the major Part of them, shall think fit, not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding the Sum of Twenty Pounds, nor under the Sum of Ten Pounds, to be Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vied by Distress and Sale of the Offenders Goods and Chattels, in like manner as by this Act is Appointed, for Levying the se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Rates and Assessments herein men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, in case of neglect or refusal of Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and to be Charged upon the respective Receivers General, together with the said Rates and Assessments; And every Asses<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sor, so as aforesaid, Appointed or to be Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, shall, before he take upon him the Execution of the said Employment, take the Oaths Mentioned and Required to be taken, by an Act made in the Parliament held in the First year of Their Majesties Reign, Intituled, <hi>An Act for the Abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointing other Oaths;</hi> and also take an Oath to be Administred in these Words following; <hi>You shall Swear well and truly to Execute the Duty of an Assessor, and to cause the Rates and Duties Imposed by an Act, Entituled, <hi>An Act for Granting to Their Majesties an Aid of Four Shillings in the Pound for One year, for Carrying on a Vigorous War a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst</hi>
                  <pb n="15" facs="tcp:180540:8"/> France, to be duly and impartially Assessed, according to the best of your Skill and Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge; and therein you shall Spare no Person for Favour or Affection, nor any Person Grieve for Hatred or Ill-will, <hi>So help you God.</hi>
               </hi> (Which Oaths any Two or more of the Commissi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners, in the County, City or Place where the said Assessment is to be made, have here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Power, and are hereby Required to Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minister.)</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That the Rates and Assess<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments upon all ready Monies, Debts, Goods, Chattels, Personal Estates, and Publick Offices and Imployments of Profit, char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged by this Act, shall be ascertained, and the Certificates thereof returned to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners upon, or before the Fifth day of <hi>March</hi> One thousand six hundred ninety and three, unless the Commissioners shall think fit to give a further time; And also the Tax<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ations and Assessments of the Pound Rate, of Four Shillings in the Pound, of the yearly value of all Manors, Messuages, Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments and Premisses charged by this Act, shall be made and ascertained, and the several and respe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Certificates thereof returned in to the Commissioners, upon, or before the Fifth day of <hi>March</hi> aforesaid, unless the Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners shall think fit to give further time; And upon return of any such Certificate, the Commissioners, or any Three or more of them shall, and may (if they see cause) Examine the Presenters thereof; And if the said Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners, or any Three or more of them,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:180540:9"/> within their several Limits, at the time of the return of the Certificates, as aforesaid, or within Twenty Days after, shall know, or have good cause to suspect, That any Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son or Persons, or any the Manors, Messua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, Lands, or other the Premisses, which ought to be Mentioned and Charged in the said Certificates, is, or are omitted; or that any Person or Persons in the said Certifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cates mentioned, is, or are of a greater E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>state, or that any the said Manors, or other Premisses, are of a greater yearly value then in the said Certificate is mentioned, the said Commissioners, or any Three, or more of them, shall have Power to Summon such Person or Persons, and the Owners and Possessors of such Manors, or other Premisses, to appear before them, at a Day and Place Prefixed, to be Examined touching the Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters aforesaid; And if the Person or Persons Summoned to be so Examined, shall neglect to appear, (not having a reasonable Excuse for such his default) every Person so ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king default, shall pay to Their Majesties double the Sum he should, or ought to have been Set at, or Rated: And moreover, The Commissioners, or the major part of so ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of them as shall be present, shall have power by all lawful ways and means, to Examine into the Estate of such Person, and the Value of such Premisses Chargeable by this Act, and to set such Rate or Rates upon the same, as shall be according to the true intent of this Act; And the said Assessors are hereby required to give one Copy of their Certificates or Assessments fairly written
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:180540:9"/> and subscribed by them, unto the said Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners by whom they were appointed, and the said Commissioners, or any Two or more of them, are hereby Ordered and Required, to cause the said several and respective Assessments to them delivered (when by them approved of, or altered ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the true intent of this Act) to be fairly Written, and to Sign and Seal several Duplicates or Copies of the said As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sessment, and one of them so Signed and Sealed forthwith to deliver or cause to be delivered unto the Subcollectors, and shall likewise deliver or cause to be delivered other Copies thereof so Signed and Sealed unto the Head Collectors and Receivers General according to their several and respective Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lections and Receipts. And moreover, the said Commissioners shall cause a true Copy or Extract of the whole Sums Assessed and Charged within every Hundred, Lathe, Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentake, Parish, Ward or Place, Rated or Assessed in pursuance of this Act, and of the whole Sums Rated or Assessed upon Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonal Estates, Offices or Imployments to be certified and transmitted into Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties Court of Exchequer, under the Hands and Seals of any Two or more of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners, but without naming the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons in such their Certificates; And this the said Commissioners shall cause to be done upon or before the Twentieth Day of <hi>March</hi> then next ensuing, or within Thirty Days after (all Appeals to them made being first determined) And the Kings Remembrancer in the Exchequer for the time being, shall
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:180540:10"/> and is hereby required, within Threé Months after the Duplicates of the last Payment shall be transmitted to him, to transcribe all the Schedules and Duplicates of the Sums returned to him from and for every re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective County, Riding, City and Town, and every Hundred, Wapentake, Parish, Division, Town and Place therein in a Book of Parchment in Alphabetical Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, and in a fair legible Hand Writing, and within Threé Months after the same shall be so by him received, to transmit all and every the same Schedules and Dupli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cates to the Office of Writer of the Tal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies, commonly called, The Auditor of the Receipt of the Exchequer, who is hereby likewise authorized and required to enter the same in the like Alphabetical Order in another Book of Parchment fairly Writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten to the provided for that purpose.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforesaid, That the Commissioners or any Two or more of them, shall Issue out their Warrants or Estreats to the Sub-Collectors under their Hands and Seals, thereby requiring them to Levy and Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect one Fourth part of the Rates and Assessments in respect of their Personal E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>states, Offices and Imployments, and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so one Fourth part of the Pound Rate Charged upon all Manors, Messuages, Lands, Tenements and Hereditaments and Premisses, as aforesaid. And the said Subcollectors are hereby required and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyned to Levy and Collect the same, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:180540:10"/> to the Duplicates thereof by them received, and according to the Intent and Directions of this Act, and to make de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand of the said Rates and Assessments, upon Personal Estates, Offices and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployments of the Parties themselves if they can be found, or otherwise at the place of their last Abode, and to pay the same unto their respective Head Collectors on or before the Fifteenth Day of <hi>March,</hi> One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand six hundred ninety threé, or within Twenty Days after. And the said Head Collectors are to hasten the said Subcol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors, and in case the same shall not be Collected by reason of Neglect or Failure of Duty of the said Subcollectors, the said Head Collectors are to Levy by Warrant under the Hands and Seals of any Two or more of the said Commissioners, by Distress upon the Subcollectors respectively, such Sum and Sums of Money as by him and them ought to have beén paid and is or are not paid, by reason of his Failure in doing his Duty, according to the Directions of this Act. And every Head Collector is hereby re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired to make Payment of what shall be so Levied or Received unto the Receiver Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral of the said County, City or Place, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on or before the Twentieth Day of <hi>March</hi> aforesaid, or within Twenty Days after: And the Receiver General is likewise re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired to call upon and hasten the said Head Collectors, and to pay what he shall receive from the said Head Collectors unto Their Majesties Receipt of Exchequer upon
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:180540:11"/> or before the Six and twentieth Day of <hi>March,</hi> One thousand six hundred ninety four, or within Twenty Days after, to the end the First Payment of the said Rates and Assessments may by that time be fully answered and paid in to Their Majesties. And the Subcollectors shall also Levy the Second Quarterly Payment of the said Rates and Assessments Charged as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, upon or before the Second Day of <hi>June</hi> then next ensuing, or within Twenty Days after, and shall also pay the same in to the Head Collectors, upon or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Ninth Day of <hi>June</hi> aforesaid, or within Twenty Days after; And the said Head Collectors shall make payment thereof to the Receivers General of the said County, City, or Place, upon, or before the Sixteénth day of <hi>June</hi> aforesaid, or within Twenty Days after; And the said Receiver General is also required to make payment of all which he shall so receive, into Their Majesties Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt of Exchequer, upon, or before the Five and twentieth day of <hi>June</hi> aforesaid, or with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in Twenty days after, to the end, that the second payment of the Rates and Assess<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments so charged as aforesaid, may by that time be fully Answered and Paid in to Their Majesties: And the said Subcollectors are also Required, and Enjoyned to Levy one other Quarterly Payment of the said Rates and Assessments Charged, as aforesaid, upon or before the Fourth Day of <hi>September,</hi> then next ensuing; and shall also Pay the same unto the said respective Head Collectors, on or before the Twelfth Day of
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:180540:11"/>
               <hi>September</hi> aforesaid, or within Twenty days after: And the said Head Collectors are to hasten the said Subcollectors, and in Case the same shall not be Collected by reason of neglect or failure of Duty in the said Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>collectors, the Head Collectors are to proceed against them by Distress, in like manner and by like Warrant, as aforesaid; And every Head Collector is hereby required to make payment of what shall be so Levied or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, unto the Receiver General of the said County, City, or Place, upon, or before the Twentieth day of <hi>September</hi> aforesaid, or within Twenty Days after; And the Recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver General is likewise required to call up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and hasten the said Head Collectors, and to pay what he shall receive from the said Head Collectors, into Their Majesties Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt of Exchequer, upon, or before the Nine and twentieth day of <hi>September</hi> aforesaid, or within Twenty days after, to the end, that the third Payment of the said Rates and Assessments may, by that time be fully An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>swered and Paid in to Their Majesties: And the Subcollectors shall also Levy one other Quarterly payment of the said Rates and Assessments charged as aforesaid, upon or before the Third day of <hi>December</hi> then next ensuing, or within Twenty days after, and shall also Pay the same unto the said Head Collectors, upon, or before the Tenth day of <hi>December</hi> aforesaid, or within Twenty days after; And the said Head Collectors shall make payment thereof to the Receiver Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral of the said County, City, or Place, up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, or before the Seventeénth day of <hi>Decem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber</hi>
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:180540:12"/> aforesaid, or within Twenty days after; And the said Receiver General is likewise required to make payment of all which he shall so receive, into Their Majesties Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceipt of Exchequer, upon, or before the Five and Twentieth day of <hi>December</hi> aforesaid, or within Twenty days after, to the end, that the Fourth and Last Quarterly Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the said Rates and Assessments so Charged as aforesaid, may by that time be fully Answered and Paid in to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sties: And all Commissioners, Collectors, and Receivers, are hereby required and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyned to apply themselves with all dili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gence, to the most speédy and effectual execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of their several and respective Duties, and to use their utmost endeavours, that all Estates herein Charged, may equally pay the Rates and Assessments, according to the direction of this Act, that so Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties Service herein may not be delayed or hindred through any of their wilful neglect or default.</p>
            <p>And it is further Enacted and Declared by the Authority aforesaid, That the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies received by the Subcollectors, within their respective Divisions or Hundreds, shall from time to time be duly paid to the Head Collectors, whose Receipt shall be a sufficient Discharge unto every such Subcollector, which Subcollector, for gathering the said particular Sums, shall retain in his Hands, for every Twenty Shillings by him so paid, Threé pence, as a Reward for his Pains and Service; And the said Head Collectors shall accordingly pay over the said Monies, unto
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:180540:12"/> the Receiver General of each County, City, or Place respectively in manner aforesaid; which Head Collector, or Collectors, shall be nominated and appointed by the Receiver General of the respective Counties, which said Receiver General shall be answerable for all such Sums of Money as shall be by him or them Collected or Received: And that no Subcollector shall be forced to Travel above the space of Ten Miles, for the payment of the said Monies that shall be by him Collect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed or Received; And the said Receiver Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rals Acquittance, shall be a sufficient Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge unto every such Head Collector: And the Receiver General shall pay the whole Sum by him Received, into the Receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer, in such manner, and at or before such days and times as are herein before limited; And shall have an al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowance of Two Pence in the Pound for all Monies which shall be by him paid into the Receipt of the Exchequer, upon, or before the times prefixt in this Act.</p>
            <p>And for the careful writing and tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scribing the said Warrants, Certificates, Estreats and Duplicates in due time, it is further Enacted, That the Commissioners Clerks who shall respectively perform the same, shall by Warrant under Two or more of the Commissioners Hands, have and receive from the respective Receivers Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral, One Peny in the Pound of all such Moneys as he or they shall have received by virtue of such Warrants and Estreats, who are hereby appointed and allowed to pay the same accordingly.</p>
            <pb n="24" facs="tcp:180540:13"/>
            <p>And be it further Enacted and Declared, That if any Person or Persons shall refuse or neglect to pay any Sum or Sums of Money whereat he or they shall be Rated and Assessed, that then it shall and may be lawful to and for the said Collectors or any of them, and he and they is and are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by authorized and required for non Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment thereof, to Levy the Sum or Sums so Rated and Assessed by Distress and Sale of the Goods and Chattels of such Person so refusing or neglecting to pay by his or their Goods or Chattels, or to Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strain upon the Messuages, Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Premisses so Charged with any such Sum or Sums, and the Goods and Chattels then and there found, and the Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stress so taken, to keep by the space of Four Days at the Costs and Charges of the Owners thereof, and if the said Owner do not pay the Sum or Sums of Money so Rated and Assessed within the space of the said Four Days, then the said Distress to be Appraised by Two or Three In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants where the same shall be taken, or other sufficient Persons, and to be sold by the Collectors for the Payment of the said Money; And the Overplus coming by such sale (if any be over and above the Charges of taking and keeping of the Distress) to be immediately returned to the Owner thereof. And moreouer, it shall be lawful to break open (in the Day time) any House, and (upon Warrant under the Hands and Seals of Two or more of the said Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners) any Chest, Trunk, Box or other
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:180540:13"/> things where any such Goods are, calling to their assistance the Constable, Tything<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men and Headboroughs within the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Cities, Towns and Places where any Refusal, Neglect or Resistance shall be made; Which said Officers are hereby re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired to be Aiding and Assisting in the Premisses, as they will Answer the contrary at their Peril; and the several and respective Tenant or Tenants of all Houses, Lands, Tenements and Heredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taments which shall be Rated by virtue of this Act, are hereby required and au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thorized to pay such Sum or Sums of Money as shall be Rated upon such Houses, Lands, Tenements or Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, and to deduct out of the Rents so much of the said Rates, as in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spect of the said Rents of every such House, Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments, the Landlord should or ought to pay and bear; And the said Landlords, both mediate and immediate, according to their respective In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terests, are hereby required to allow such deductions in Payments, upon the receipt of the residue of their Rents.</p>
            <p>And it is Enacted and Declared, That every Tenant paying the said Assessments, shall be acquitted and discharged for so much Money as the said Assessments shall Amount unto, as if the same had been actually paid unto such Person and Persons unto whom his Rents should have been Due and Payable; And if any Person or Persons so Rated or Charged, do find him or themselves agrieved with such Assessing
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:180540:14"/> or Rating, and do within Ten Days after Demand made of the Sum or Sums of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney Assessed on him or them, Complain to the Commissioners, the said Commissioners, or any Three or more of them, so as the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor Part of the Commissioners who Signed or Allowed his or their Rates be present, shall have, and have hereby Power, within Ten Days, next after such Complaint, particularly to Examine any Person or Persons, upon his or their Oath, touching the Value of his or their Real or Personal Estate, and other the Matters aforesaid; and upon due Examination and Knowledge thereof, Allow, Abate, Defaulk, Encrease, or Enlarge the said Assessment, and the same so Allowed, Abated, Encreased or En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>larged, shall be Levied, and shall be Certi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied or Estreated into the Exchequer, in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner aforesaid; and to that end, the said Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners are hereby required to Meet toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther for the determining of such Complaints and Appeals accordingly; and for this end, to Express in their Warrants to the Collect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ors, the Times and Places for Determining Appeals, and Appeals once Heard and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termined, to be final, without any further Appeal upon any pretence whatsoever.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted and Declared by the Authority aforesaid, That if any Asses<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sor, Collector, Receiver, or other Person ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the said Commissioners, shall wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully neglect, or refuse to perform his or their Duty, in the due and speedy execution of this present Act; or if any Assessor shall witting<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly or willingly Vnder Rate, or Assess at an
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:180540:14"/> Vnder Value any Person or Thing Charge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able by this Act, the said respective Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners, or any Three or more of them, have hereby Power to Impose on such Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son or Persons, so refusing, neglecting or not performing their Duties, such Fine or Fines, as by them shall be thought fit, so as the same exceed not the Sum of Twenty Pounds, nor to be under the Sum of Ten Pounds; which said Fines shall not be taken off or discharged, but by the Consent of the majority of the Commissioners who Impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed the same, but shall be Levyed by War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant under the Hands and Seals of the said Commissioners, or any Two of them, by Distress and Sale of the Goods and Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels of the Offenders; and in default of Goods and Chattels, the Offenders to be Committed (by Warrant under the Hands and Seals of the said Commissioners) to Prison, there to remain till Payment of the said Fines; And that all Fines that shall be Imposed by Virtue of this Act, shall be paid to the respective Receivers General, and by them into the Receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer.</p>
            <p>And it is further Enacted and Declared, That if any Collector that shall (by virtue of this Act, be appointed for the Receipt of any Sums of Money thereby to be Assessed) neglect, or refuse to pay any Sum or Sums of Money, which shall be by him received as aforesaid, and to pay the same as in and by this Act is directed, and shall detain in his or their Hands, any Money received by them or any of them, and not pay the same at such
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:180540:15"/> time as by this Act is directed, The Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners of each County, Riding, City or Town respectively, or any Two or more of them, in their respective Divisions, are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Authorized and Impowered to Imprison the Person, and Seize and Secure the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>state both Real and Personal, of such Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors to him belonging, or which shall de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scend or come into the Hands or Possession of his Heirs, Executors or Administrators, wheresoever the same can be discovered and found, and the said Commissioners who shall so Seize and Secure the Estate of any Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lector or Collectors, shall be, and are hereby impowered to appoint a time for the General Meéting of the Commissioners, for such County, Riding, City, Town, or Place, and there to cause Publick Notice to be given at the Place where such Meeting shall be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, Six Days at least before such Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Meéting; And the Commissioners present at such General Meeting, or the major part of them, in case the Moneys detained by any such Collector or Collectors, be not paid or sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfied, as it ought to be, according to the Directions of this Act, shall, and are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by impowered and required to sell and dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pose of all such Estates, which shall be for the Cause aforesaid Seized and Secured, or any part of them, and to satisfie and pay into the Hands of the Receiver General, the Sum that shall be so detained in the Hands of such Collector or Collectors, their Heirs, Executors, or Administrators respectively.</p>
            <p>And it is hereby further Enacted and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared, That at the Expiration of the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:180540:15"/> times in this in this Act prescribed for the full Payment of the said Four Quarterly Payments, the several and respective Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners, or any Two or more of them within their Division and Hundred, shall and are hereby required to call before them the Collectors within each respective Division, Hundred, Parish and Place, to Examine and assure themselves of the full and whole Payment of the particular Sum and Sums of Money Charged within and upon the same Division, Hundred, and every Parish and Place therein, and of the due Return of the same into the Hands of the Receivers General, Their Deputy or Deputies of the said County, Riding, City, Town and Place respectively, and by such Receiver Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral into the Receipt of Their Majesties Exchequer; to the end there may be no failure in the Payment of any part of the Assessment by virtue of this Act to be As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sessed and Paid; And in case of any failure in the Premisses, the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them are hereby to cause the same to be forthwith Levied and Paid according to the true intent and meaning of this Act.</p>
            <p>And it is hereby Enacted and Declared, That in case any Controversie arise concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the said Assessment, or the Dividing, Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portioning or Payment thereof, which con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerns any the Commissioners by this Act appointed, that the Commissioners so con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerned in the said Controversie shall have no Voice, but shall withdraw at the time of the Debate of any such Controversie, until
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:180540:16"/> it be determined by the rest of the Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners, and in default thereof, that the Commissioners then present shall have power, and are hereby required to impose such Fine and Fines, as to them shall be thought fit, upon such Commissioners so re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fusing to withdraw, not exceeding the Sum of Twenty Pounds, and to cause the same to be Levied and Paid, as other Fines to be imposed by this Act are to be Levied and paid; And all Questions and Diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rences that shall arise touching any the said Rates, Assessments or Levies, or the Collecting thereof, shall be heard and finally determined by the Commissioners in such manner as by this Act is directed, upon Complaint thereof made to them by any Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son or Persons thereby agrieved, without further trouble or suit in Law.</p>
            <p>Provided, That nothing contained in this Act shall extend to Charge any College or Hall in either of the Two Vniversities, or the Colleges of <hi>Windsor, Eaton, Winchester</hi> or <hi>Westminster,</hi> or the Corporation of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ours of the Charity for Relief of Poor Widows and Children of Clergymen, or the College of <hi>Bromley,</hi> or any Hospital for or in respect of the Scites of the said Colleges, Halls or Hospitals, or any Master, Fellow or Scholar of any such College or Halls, or any Reader, Officer or Minister of the said Vniversities, Colleges or Halls, or any Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sters or Vshers of any School for or in respect of any Stipend, Wages or Profits whatso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever arising or growing due to them in respect of the said several Pl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> and Employments
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:180540:16"/> in the said Vniversities, Colleges or Schools, or to Charge any of the Houses or Lands belonging to Christs Hospital, Saint <hi>Bartho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lomews, Bridewell,</hi> Saint <hi>Thomas</hi> and <hi>Bethle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hem</hi> Hospital, in the City of <hi>London</hi> and Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> or any of them; or the said Corporation of the Governours of the Charity for Relief of poor Widows and Children or Clergymen, or the College of <hi>Bromley;</hi> nor to extend to Charge any the Almsmen or Almswomen, or other Poor Persons inhabiting within any other Hospi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal or Almshouse, for or in respect of any Rents or Revenues payable to them, or any such of them, for their immediate Vse and Relief, whose Annual Maintenance and Profits shall not exceed in the whole the Sum of Twenty Pounds.</p>
            <p>Provided that no Tenants of any Lands or Houses, by Lease or Grant from the said Corporation, or any of the said Hospitals or Almshouses, do Claim or Enjoy any Freé<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom or Exemption by this Act: But that all the Houses and Lands which they so hold, shall be Rated and Assessed for so much as they are yearly worth, over and above the Rents reserved and payable to the said Corporation, or to the said Hospitals or Almshouses, to be received and disbursed for the immediate support and relief of the Poor in the said Hospitals and Almshouses.</p>
            <p>Provided also, that where any Person in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habiting within the City of <hi>London,</hi> or any other Cities or Towns Corporate, hath his Dwelling house in one of the Parishes and Wards therein, and hath any Goods,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:180540:17"/> Wares, or Merchandizes, Chargeable by this Act, in one or more of the other Pari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>shes or Wards in the same City, That then such Person shall be Charged, Taxed and As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sessed for such his Goods and Merchandizes, in the Parish or Ward where he dwelleth, and not elsewhere in the said City.</p>
            <p>Provided, and be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That for the avoiding all Obstructions and Delays in Assessing and Collecting the Sums, which by this Act are to be Rated and Assessed, all Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tes, Constable wicks, Divisions and Allot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, which have used to be Rated and As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sessed, shall Pay and be Assessed in such County, Hundred, Rape, Wapentake, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stablewick, Division, Place and Allotment, as the same hath heretofore usually been As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sessed in, and not elsewhere.</p>
            <p>Provide always, That nothing in this Act Contained shall be Construed to Alter, Change, Determine or make Void any Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracts, Covenants or Agreements whatso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, between Landlord and Tenant, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny others, touching the Payment of Taxes or Assessments, any thing herein before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforesaid, That if any Action, Plaint, Suit or Information shall be commenced or prosecuted against any Person or Persons for what he or they shall do in pursuance or in Execution of this Act, such Person or Persons (so sued in any Court whatsoever) shall and may plead the General Issue (not Guilty) and upon any Issue joyned, may
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:180540:17"/> give this Act, and the Special Matter in Evidence, and if the Plantiff or Prosecutor shall become Nonsuit, or forbear further Prosecution, or suffer a Discontinuance, or if a Verdict pass against him, the Defendants shall recover their Treble Costs, for which they shall have the like remedy as in any Case where Costs by the Law are given to Defendants. And the said Receivers Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral shall give Acquittances <hi>(gratis)</hi> to the said Head Collectors for all Moneys of them received; And the said Head Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors shall also give Acquittances <hi>(gratis)</hi> to the Subcollectors for all such Moneys as shall be paid them in pursuance of this Act; And the said Subcollectors shall make and deliver to the said Head Collectors a perfect Schedule fairly written in Parchment, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der their Hands and Seals, Signed and Allowed by any Two or more of the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective Commissioners, containing the Names, Sirnames and Places of Abode of every Person within their respective Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lections that shall make Default of Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of any of the Sums that shall be Rated or Assessed on such Person by virtue of this Act, where no sufficient Distress is to be found, nor other satisfaction made, and not otherwise, and the Sum and Sums Charged on every such Person; The same Schedule to be delivered by the Head Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lectors to the Receiver General of the County, City or Place respectively, to be by him returned into Their Majesties Court of Exchequer; Whereupon every Person so making Default of Payment, may be
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:180540:18"/> Charged by Process of the said Court, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Course of the Court of Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer in such Cases.</p>
            <p>Provided always and be it further En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted, That in case any Lands or Houses in any Parish or Constablewick shall lie Vnoccupied, and no Distress can be found on the same, nor the Person of the true Owner or Proprietor can be found within the County wherein such House or Land lieth, by reason whereof the Rate and As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sessment upon such Vnoccupied House and Lands cannot be Levied, that then upon complaint made thereof to the Commissi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners for the County where such Case shall happen to be, the said Commissioners or any Two or more of them shall Certifie into Their Majesties Court of Exchequer the Name of the Person whose Lands or House so lieth Vnoccupied, together with the Sum thereupon Assessed, and the Parish or Place where such Land or House lieth; which Certificate is hereby Declared to be a suffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent Charge upon the Person and Land or House therein named, and shall make the Person Debtor to Their Majesties for the Sum so Assessed, and the Court of Exchequer shall Issue out Process thereupon against the Body, Goods and all other the Lands of such Debtor, until the Sum so Assessed be fully and actually Levied and Paid to Their Majesties.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That where any Wood-lands shall be Assessed, and no Distress can be had, That in such Case, it shall, and may be lawful to,
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:180540:18"/> and for any Collector, Constable, Head-borough, or Tythingman, by Warrant un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Hands and Seals of two or more of the Commissioners of that Hundrred or Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vision, at seasonable times of the year, to Cut and Sell to any Person or Persons, so much of the Wood growing on the Wood<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lands (Timber-Treés excepted) so Assessed, as will pay the Assessment or Assessments to be behind and unpaid, and the Charge in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cident thereunto; And that it shall and may be lawful for the Person and Persons, and his and their Assigns, to whom such Woods shall be sold, to Fell, Cut down, and Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pose, and Carry away the same to his own Vse, rendring the Overplus (if any be) to the Owner, any Law to the contrary not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withstanding.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it further En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted, That where any Tax or Assessment shall be Charged or laid upon any Tythes, Tolls, Profits of Markets, Fairs, or Fish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ery, or other Annual Profits not Distrain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, in case the same shall not be paid with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in Fifteén days after such Assessment so Charged, or Laid, and Demanded, Then it shall and may be lawful, to, and for the Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lector, Constable, or other Officer thereunto appointed, by Warrant under the Hands and Seals of Threé or more Commissioners, Authorized by this Act, to Seize, Take, and Sell so much of the said Tythes, Tolls, and other Profits so Charged, as shall be sufficient for the Levying of the said Tax and Assessment, and all Charges occasioned by such Non-payment thereof, rendring the Overplus to the Owner, if any be.</p>
            <pb n="36" facs="tcp:180540:19"/>
            <p>And for the better preventing of such un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>just Vexations, as might be occasioned by such Persons as shall be appointed Receivers General of any of the Sums of Money granted by this Act; And to the intent that the said Receivers General may return a true Account into Their Majesties Court of Exchequer, of such Sums of Money as shall be received by them, and every of them, their, and every of their Deputy and Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties; Be it further Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforesaid, That if any such Receiver General return, or certify into the said Court, any Sum or Sums of Money to be in Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rear or Vnpaid, after the same have beén re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, either by such Receiver General, or by his Deputy or Deputies, or any of them, or shall cause any Person or Persons to be set <hi>Insuper,</hi> in the said Court, for any Sum or Sums of Money that hath beén so received; That then every such Receiver General shall be liable to pay to every Person and Persons, that shall be molested, vexed, or damaged, by reason of such unjust Certificate, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn, or Setting <hi>Insuper,</hi> Treble the Dama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges that shall be thereby occasioned; the said Damages to be recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information, in which no Essoign, Protection, or Wager of Law shall be Allowed, nor any more then one Impar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lance, and shall also Forfeit to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sties, Their Heirs and Successors, double the Sum that shall be so unjustly Certified or Returned, or cause to be set <hi>Insuper.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That where any Person or
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:180540:19"/> Persons, Chargeable with any Rates or Assessments by this Act imposed, shall be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Age of One and twenty years, in every such Case, the Parents, Guardians and Tutors of such Infants respectively, upon default of Payment by such Infants, shall be, and are hereby made liable to, and charged with the Payments which such In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fants ought to have made: And if such Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rents, Guardians or Tutors, shall neglect or refuse to Pay, as aforesaid, it shall and may be Lawful to proceed against them, in like manner as against any other Person or Persons, making default of Payment as herein is mentioned. And all Parents, Guar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dians and Tutors, making Payment, as aforesaid, shall be Allowed all and every the Sums paid for such Infants, upon his or their Accounts.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted, That every Person Rated or Assessed for his Office or Employment, shall be Rated and Pay for his said Office and Employment in the County, City or Place, where such Office or Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployment is Executed. And every Person who is or shall be Rated for, or in respect of any Personal Estate to him any way be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing, shall be Rated at such Place where he or she shall be Resident at the time of the Execution of this Act; And all Persons not being Housholders, nor having a certain Place of Residence, shall be Taxed at the Place where they shall be Resident at the time of the Execution of this Act. And if any Person who ought to be Taxed by virtue of this Act, for or in respect of his Personal E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>state,
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:180540:20"/> shall at the time of his Assessment, be out of the Realm, such Person shall be Rated therefore in such County, City or Place where he was last abiding within the Realm.</p>
            <p>Provided that where any Person shall have any Goods, Wares or Merchandizes, in any County or Counties, other then the County where he shall be resident, or had his last residence, it shall be lawful to Rate or Assess such Person, for such Goods, Wares and Merchandizes in the County, or Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties where the same shall be; And every Person who shall be Rated, or Assessed as aforesaid, for, or in respect of any Manors, Messuages, Lands, Tenements or Heredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taments, shall be Rated and Assessed in the Place where such Messuages, Manors, Lands, Tenements and Premisses respect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ively do lye, and not elsewhere.</p>
            <p>Provided always, That if any Person or Persons, by reason of his or their having several Mansion-houses, or Places of Resi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence or otherwise, shall be doubly Charged by occasion of this Act, for, or in respect of his or their personal Estate, Then upon Certificate made by two or more of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners for the County, Riding, City or Place of his or their last Personal Residence, under their Hands and Seals, of the Sum or Sums Charged upon him or them, and in what Capacity or Respect he or they were so Charged, (which Certificate the said Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners are required to give, without Delay, Feé, or Reward) And upon Oath made of such Certificate before any one Iustice of the Peace of the County or Place where the said
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:180540:20"/> Certificate shall be made, (which Oath the said Iustice of Peace is hereby Authorized and Required to Administer) then the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son and Persons so doubly Charged, shall for so much as shall be so certified, be Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged in every other County, City, or Place: And if any Person that ought to be Taxed by virtue of this Act, for, or in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spect of his Personal Estate, shall by chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging his place of Residence, or by any other fraud or covin escape from the Taxation, and not be Taxed, and the same be proved before the Commissioners, or any Two of them, or before any Iustice of the Peace in the County, Riding, City, or Place where such Person dwelleth or resideth, at any time within One year next ensuing after such Tax made, every Person that shall so escape from the Taxation and Payment, shall be charged (upon proof thereof) at the double value of so much as he should, or ought to have beén Taxed at, by this Act; the said double value, upon Certificate thereof made into the Exchequer by the Commissioners or Iustices (before whom such proof shall be made) to be Levied of the Goods, Lands and Tenements of such Person.</p>
            <p>And for the better discovery of Personal Estates, Be it further Enacted by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforesaid, That every Housholder shall upon the Demand of the Assessors of the respective Parishes or Places, give an Account of the Names and Qualities of such Persons as shall Sojourn or Lodge in their respective Houses, under the Penalty of forfeiting to Their Majesties the Sum of
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:180540:21"/> Twenty Pounds to be Levied and Recover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in such manner as other Penalties in this Act mentioned are to be Levied and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covered.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforesaid, That the Commissioners that shall be within any County, City or Place within the respective Limits, or the Major part of them, shall Rate, Tax and Assess every other Commissioner joyned with them for and in respect of the ready Money, Debts, Goods, Chattels and Personal Estate of such Commissioners; And also for and in respect of the Offices and Employments of Profit which at the time of such Examina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion shall be held and enjoyed by such Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners, so as the residence and usual dwelling-place of such Commissioner, so to be Taxed, be within the Division of such Commissioners by whom he is Taxed, and so as the Office and Employment held and enjoyed by such Commissioner, so to be Tax<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, be likewise to be Exercised within the Division or Limits of such Commissioners by whom he is to be Taxed, and the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners within their Division shall also Assess every Assessor within their Division for all and singular the Premisses for which by this Act he ought to be Rated and Asses<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed; And as well all Sums Assessed upon every the said Commissioners and Assessors, as the Assessmens made and set by the Assessors aforesaid, shall be Written Estreated, Levied and Gathered as the same should and ought to have been, if such Commissioners had not been named Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners.</p>
            <pb n="41" facs="tcp:180540:21"/>
            <p>And be it further Enacted and Ordained by the Authority aforesaid, That all and every Person and Persons, having any Share or Shares or Interest in any Fresh Stream or Running Water brought to the <hi>North</hi> parts of <hi>London,</hi> commonly called, <hi>The New River,</hi> or in the <hi>Thames</hi> Water-works, or in the <hi>Hide Park,</hi> or <hi>Marybone</hi> Waters, or any Rents or Profits arising thereby; And all Person and Persons having any Share or Interest in the Stock or Stocks of Printing of Books in or belonging to the House commonly called, <hi>The Kings Printing House,</hi> shall pay for the same the Sum of Four Shillings for every Twenty Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings of the full Yearly Value thereof; And they and all Companies of Merchants in <hi>London,</hi> Charged by this Act, shall be As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sessed by the Commissioners Nominated and Appointed for the said City, or any Threé of them, for their respective Shares and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terests aforesaid, and the aforesaid Ioynt Stock and Stocks; And the same shall be paid by the Governours and respective Treasurers of the said respective Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies, and by the Treasurers or Receivers of the said River, Waters and Water-works, and Stock for Printing, and be De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducted at and out of their next Dividend.</p>
            <p>Provided also, That this Act shall not ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to the Inhabitants of <hi>Scotland, Ireland, Jersey</hi> or <hi>Guernsey,</hi> for and concerning any such Personal Estate which they or any to their use have within the Places aforesaid.</p>
            <p>And it is further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That the said Commissioners,
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:180540:22"/> or any Two or more of them, may, and shall from time to time call for, and require an Account from the respective Receivers Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral of all the Moneys received by them of the said Collectors, and of the payments thereof into Their Majesties Receipt of Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer, according to the direction of this Act, and in case of any failure in the Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>misses, the said Commissioners, or any two or more of them, are hereby required to cause the same to be forthwith Levied and Paid, according to the true intent and meaning of this Act.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That no Letters Patents granted by Their Majesties, or any of Their Royal Progenitors, to any Person or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons, Cities, Boroughs or Towns Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate within this Realm, of any manner of Liberties, Priviledges, or Exemptions from Subsidies, Tolls, Taxes, Assessments or Aids, shall be construed, or taken to exempt any Person or Persons, City, Borough or Town-Corporate, or any of the Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants of the same, or in the Tower of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> from the Burthen and Charge of any Sum or Sums of Money granted by this Act; but that all and every such Person and Persons, City, Borough, and Town Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porate, shall pay their Proportions of all Rates and Assessments by this present Act imposed, any such Letters Patents, Grants, or Charters, or any Clause of <hi>Non obstante,</hi> Matter or Thing therein contained, or any Law, Statute, Custom or Prescription to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
            <pb n="43" facs="tcp:180540:22"/>
            <p>Provided also, that no Person inhabiting in any City, Borough, or Town-Corporate shall be compelled to be any Assessor or Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lector of, or for any part of the Rates and Assessments hereby Granted in any Place or Places out of the Limits of the said City, Borough, or Town-Corporate.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That every Rate, Tax or Assessment which shall be made, or imposed by virtue of this Act, in respect of any House or Tenement which an Ambassador, Resident, Agent, or other Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Minister of any Foreign Prince or State now doth, or hereafter shall inhabit or occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>py, shall be paid by the Landlord or Owner of the said House, or Tenements respectively.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That in all Priviledged and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Places, being Extraparochial, or not within any the Constablewicks, or Precincts of the respective Assessors, to be appointed by virtue of this Act (although in any month<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, or other Tax, they have not beén Assessed or Rated heretofore) the said Commissioners, or any Two or more of them, shall, and are hereby required to nominate and appoint Two fit Persons, living in or near the said Priviledged or other Places as aforesaid, to be Assessors for the said Places, and to make and return their said Assessments in like manner as by this Act is appointed, in any Parish, Tything or Place; And also to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point One or more Collectors, who are hereby required to Collect, and Pay the same accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Rates appointed by this Act, for Collecting and Paying all Sums of Money payable by this Act.</p>
            <pb n="44" facs="tcp:180540:23"/>
            <p>Provided always, and be it further En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by the Authority aforesaid, That no Commissioner or Commissioners, who shall be imployed in the Execution of this Act, shall be liable for or by reason of such Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecution, to any of the Penalties men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned in an Act made in the Five and twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tieth Year of the Reign of King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second, for the preventing of Dangers which may happen from Popish Recusants.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That no Person shall be capable of Acting as a Commissioner in the Execution of this Act, before he shall have taken the Oaths appointed by an Act of Parliament made in the First Year of Their Majesties Reign, Entituled, <hi>An Act for the Abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing other Oaths,</hi> which Oaths it shall be lawful for any Two or more Commissioners to Administer, and are hereby required to Administer to any other Commissioners.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforesaid, That every Papist, or repu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Papist, being of the Age of Sixteen Years and upwards, who shall not have taken the Oaths mentioned and required to be taken by the said last mentioned Act, shall Yield and Pay unto Their Majesties double the Sums and Rates which by Force or Virtue of any Clause in this Act before mentioned or contained, he or she should or ought to pay or be charged with, to be Assessed, Levied and Collected, Answered, Recovered and Paid in such manner, by such ways and means, and according to such Rules and Directions, and
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:180540:23"/> under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are before in this Act expressed or appointed for and concerning the above mentioned Rates and Sums which are hereby intended to be doubled, as aforesaid.</p>
            <p>Provided nevertheless, That if any such Papist, or reputed Papist, within Ten Days after the first Meéting of the said Commissi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners, in the respective Counties or Places, where he or she ought to be Taxed or Assessed according to the intent of this present Act, shall take the said Oaths before Two or more of the said Commissioners (which Oaths the said Commissioners are hereby impowered to Administer) that in such case he or she shall not be liable to be doubly Assessed, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That every person being of the Age of Sixteén years or upwards, and being within this Realm at the time of the Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of this Act, who shall not before that time have taken the Oaths mentioned and required to be taken by the said Act, Entitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, <hi>An Act for the Abrogating of the Oaths of Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>premacy and Allegiance, and Appointing other Oaths;</hi> And upon Summons by Warrant under the Hand and Seal of any Two or more of the Commissioners appointed by this Act, shall refuse to take the said Oaths at the time appointed in the said Warrant, or shall neglect to appear at such time before the Commissioners, in order to take the said Oaths (which Oaths the said Commission<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, or any Two or more of them, are hereby impowered and required to Admini<gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>er shall
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:180540:24"/> yield, and pay unto Their Majesties double the Sums and Rates, which by force or vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of any Clause in this Act before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned or contained, he or she should, or ought to pay, or be charged with, in manner as is before in this present Act appointed, touching Papists or Reputed Papists.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity aforesaid, That every Gentleman, or so reputed, or owning or writing himself such, or being above that Quality, who by virtue of an Act made in the Third Year of Their Majesties Reign, Entituled, <hi>An Act for Rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing Money by a Poll, payable quarterly for one Year, for carrying on a Vigorous War against <hi>France,</hi>
               </hi> did pay, or ought to have paid, double the Sums charged by the said Act, or were, or ought to have beén Returned into the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer for non-payment thereof, who shall not voluntarily appear before the said Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners, or any Two or more of them, within Ten days after the first Meeting of the said Commissioners, in the respective place or places where he ought to be Taxed or Assessed, and take the said Oaths appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the said Act, made in the first year of Their Majesties Reign (which Oaths the said Commissioners, or any Two or more of them, are hereby impowered and required to Administer, and to make an Entry or Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>morandum thereof in some Book to be kept for that purpose) such Person shall be char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged with, and pay double the Sums which by force or virtue of this Act, he should, or ought to have paid; to be Assessed, Levied, Collected, Answered, Recovered, and Paid in such
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:180540:24"/> manner, by such ways and means, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to such Rules and Directions, and under such Penalties and Forfeitures as are before in this Act expressed or appointed, for, or concerning the above mentioned Rates and Sums, which are hereby intended to be doubled, as aforesaid.</p>
            <p>And be it further Enacted, That any One or more of the Commissioners appointed by this Act, upon Information given, or upon any cause of suspicion in that behalf, shall, and are hereby required and enjoyned to cause every Person suspected, or against whom such Information shall be given to be Summoned to appear to take the said Oaths, as aforesaid.</p>
            <p>Provided nevertheless, That whereas cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Persons, Dissenters from the Church of <hi>England,</hi> commonly called <hi>Quakers,</hi> and now known to be such, do scruple the taking of any Oath, It shall be sufficient for every such person, to make and subscribe the Declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Fidelity, contained in an Act made in the Parliament held in the First year of Their Majesties Reign, Entituled, <hi>An Act for Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>empting Their Majesties Protestant Subjects, Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>senting from the Church of <hi>England,</hi> from the Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalties of certain Laws;</hi> which Declaration any Two or more of the Commissioners appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for the Execution of this Act, are hereby impowered and required to take, and every such person so doing, shall not be liable to, or chargeable with any of the double Rates a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid.</p>
            <p>Provided that no poor person shall be char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged with, or liable unto the Pound Rate im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posed
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:180540:25"/> by this Act, upon Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments, whose Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments or Hereditaments are not of the year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Value of Twenty Sillings in the whole.</p>
            <p>Provided always, That the Right Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable the Master of the Rolls, the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sters of Chancery, Six Clerks, Clerks of the Petty Bag, Examiners, Registers, Clerks of the Inrollment, Clerks of the Affidavits and Subpena Office, and all others the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers of the Court of Chancery, that Exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute their Offices within the Liberty of the Rolls, shall be there Assessed for their respe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Offices, and not elsewhere.</p>
            <p>Be it further Enacted, That if any Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lector of any Parish or Place shall keep in his Hands any part of the Money by him Collected for any longer time then is by this Act directed (other then the allowance made unto him by this Act) or shall pay any part thereof to any Person or Persons other then to the Head Collector or Receiver General of such County or Place or his respective De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty, that every such Collector shall forfeit for every such Offence the Sum of Ten Pounds; And in case any Head Collector shall keep in his Hands any part of the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney paid to him by any Collector by virtue of this Act, for any longer time then is by virtue of this Act directed, or shall pay any part thereof to any Person or Persons o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther then the Receiver General of such Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty or Place, or his Deputy, every such Head Collector shall forfeit for every such Offence the Sum of Fourty Pounds; And in case any Receiver General, or his Deputy, shall
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:180540:25"/> pay any part of the Moneys paid to him or them by any Collector, by virtue of this Act, to any Person or Persons whatsoever (other then the Receipt of Their Majesties Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer, and at or within the respective times limited by this Act) or in case such Receiver General, or his Deputy, shall pay any part of the said Moneys by any Warrant of the Commissioners of the Treasury, or the Lord Treasurer, Vnder Treasurer or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners of the Treasury for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or upon any Tally of <hi>Pro,</hi> or Tally of <hi>Anticipation,</hi> or other way or device whatso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, whereby to divert or hinder the actual payment thereof into the Receipt of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer, as aforesaid, that then such Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver General shall for every such Offence of himself, or his Deputy, forfeit the Sum of One thousand Pounds to him or them that shall Sue for the same in any Court of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord, by Bill, Plaint or other Information, wherein no Essoign, Protection or Wager of Law is to be allowed.</p>
            <p>And it is hereby further Enacted, That the Commissioners of the Treasury, or the Lord Treasurer, Vnder Treasurer or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners of the Treasury for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or any of them, do not direct any War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant to any of the said Head Collectors, or Receivers General, or their Deputy, for the payment of any part of the Moneys hereby given to any Person or Persons, other then into the Receipt of the Exchequer, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said; Nor shall they or any of them direct a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Warrant to the Officers of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer for the striking of any Tally of
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:180540:26"/>
               <hi>Pro,</hi> or Tally of <hi>Anticipation,</hi> nor do any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther matter or thing whereby to divert the actual payment of the said Moneys into the Receipt of the Exchequer; Nor shall the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers of the Exchequer, Strike or Direct, or Record the striking of any Tally of <hi>Pro,</hi> or Tally of <hi>Anticipation,</hi> upon any of the said Moneys, upon any Account or Warrant whatsoever; Nor shall any Teller throw down any Bill whereby to Charge himself with any of the said Moneys, until he shall have actually received the same.</p>
            <p>Provided also and be it Enacted, That no Stay of Prosecution upon any Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand, Warrant, Motion, or Order, or Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection by <hi>non vult ulterius prosequi</hi> shall be had, made, admitted, received or allowed by any Court whatsoever, in any Suit or Proceeding by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information or otherwise for the recovery of all or any the Pains, Penalties or For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitures, upon any Person or Persons by this Act inflicted or therein mentioned, or for or in Order to the Conviction or Disabili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of any Person Offending against this Act.</p>
            <p>Provided also and be it Enacted, That no Person shall be capable of acting as a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioner in the Execution of this Act for a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny County or Riding, or the Cities of <hi>London</hi> or <hi>Westminster,</hi> unless he was Assessed, and did pay to Their Majesties the Sum of Twenty Shillings Quarterly towards the Rates and Assessments, Granted by an Act made in the Third year of Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sties Reign, Entituled, <hi>An Act for Raising
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:180540:26"/> Money by a Poll, payable Quarterly for One year, for the Carrying on a Vigorous War against <hi>France;</hi>
               </hi> or the Sum of Four Pounds to the Act made in the Fourth year of Their Majesties Reign, Entituled, <hi>An Act of Review of the Quarterly Poll Granted to Their Majesties in the last Session of this present Parliament:</hi> And also that no Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son shall be capable of acting as a Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioner in Execution of this Act, for any other City, or in any Borough, Town or Cinque Port, or the Counties thereof respectively, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>less he was Assessed, and did Pay to Their Majesties the Sum of Twenty Shillings Quarterly, as aforesaid; or was Assessed and did Pay to Their Majesties the Sum of Then Shillings Quarterly (as a Tradesman worth Three hundred Pounds) towards the said Quarterly Poll; or the Sum of Fourty Shillings to the said Act for Review of the said Quar terly Poll.</p>
            <p>Provided always, That every Person who did pay to Their Majesties the Sum of Ten Shillings Quarterly (as a Tradesman worth Three hundred Pounds) toward the said Quarterly Poll, may be capable of act<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing as a Commissioner, for and within any City, Borough or Town-Corporate, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of he is an Inhabitant, although he was Nominated a Commissioner for the County at large, in which such City, Borough or Town-Corporate is scituate, unless Commissioners were particularly Appointed by the said Act for such City, Borough or Town-Corporate.</p>
            <p>Provided nevertheless, That in Case there shall not be a sufficient number of Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners for any City, Town and County of
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:180540:27"/> the same Borough, Town or Cinque Port (for which, by this Act, Commissioners are particularly appointed) capable of Acting according to the Qualifications afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said for putting this Act in Execution, that in every such Case, any of the Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners appointed for the County at large, within which, such Cities, Towns and Counties of the same Borough, Town, or Cinque Port doth stand, or which is next ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyning thereto, may act as Commissioners in the execution of this Act, within such City, Town and County of the same Borough, Town, or Cinque Port.</p>
            <p>Provided also, and be it further Enacted, That in case there shall not be a sufficient number of the persons nominated to be Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missioners for any County, who shall be ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pable of acting as Commissioners, according to the qualifications in this Act before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, That in every such Case it shall be Lawful for Their Majesties to issue or cause to be issued one or more Commission or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>missions under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> and thereby to nominate, constitute and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point such, and so many persons being Resi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent, and having real Estates of the value of One hundred Pounds a year in the said re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective Counties, for which they shall be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spectively nominated to be Commissioners for putting this present Act in Execution in the said Counties respectively, which said Commissioners so to be nominated and appointed for the said Counties respectively shall have such and the same Powers for put<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting this Act in Execution in the said re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:180540:27"/> Counties, and under the same Rules and Directions, as any other Commis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sioners Nominated or Appointed by this Act, any thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
            <p>And for the more effectual Charging all Personal Estates, Be it Enacted by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforesaid, That if after the Assess<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments on Personal Estates directed by this Act shall be made, any Person shall come to Inhabit or Reside in any Division or Place where such Person was not Rated or Taxed for Personal Estate, the Commissioners act<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing within such Division or Place, are hereby Required and Impowered to Summon such Person before them; and unless he or she shall produce a Certificate made according to the Directions of this Act, whereby it shall ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear that he or she was Assessed, and had actu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally paid all the precedent Quarterly Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, in some other place for his or her Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonal Estate, the said Commissioners shall, and are hereby Required to cause such person to be Assessed for his or her Personal Estate, and cause the same, or such Quarterly Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments thereof as shall be Vnassessed and Vnpaid, to be Assessed, Levied and Paid, according to the true Intent and Meaning of this Act.</p>
            <p>Provided always, That the Prison of the <hi>Kings-Bench,</hi> the Prison-House, Lands, Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens and the Common side, and all the Rents, Profits and Perquisites of the Office of the Marshal of the said <hi>Kings-Bench</hi> Prison, lying and being in the Parish of Saint <hi>George</hi> the Martyr in the Borough of <hi>Southwark</hi> and
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:180540:28"/> County of <hi>Surrey,</hi> and also the Prison-House, Lands and Gardens of the Prison of the Marshal of the <hi>Marshalsea</hi> Prison, and all Offices, Perquisites and Profits of the <hi>Marshalsea</hi> Court and Prison, lying and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing also in the said Parish of Saint <hi>George</hi> in the Borough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> and County of <hi>Surrey,</hi> shall be Charged and Assessed to this Assessment in the said Parish of Saint <hi>George,</hi> and Borough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> and not elsewhere, any thing to the contrary in any wise notwithstanding.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That if any person hereby named a Commissioner, shall presume to act as a Commissioner in the Execution of this Act, before he shall have taken the Oaths which by this Act he is re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired to take, and in the manner hereby pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scribed, he shall forfeit to Their Majesties the Sum of Five hundred Pounds.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That where the Owners of any Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Hereditaments are liable to be doubly charged as Papists, Reputed Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pists, or otherwise by reason of their not ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving taken the Oaths according to the intent of this Art, in every such Case, such Owners only shall be charged with, and shall pay the said double Rates; And the respective Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants of such Lands, Tenements and He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, are hereby discharged of, and from the same, any Covenant for payment of Taxes, or other Agreément to the contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry notwithstanding.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That all the Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terworks
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:180540:28"/> in the Borough of <hi>Southwark</hi> shall be Rated and Assessed by the Commission<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers and Assessors of the County of <hi>Surrey,</hi> and not by the Commissioners or Assessors for the City of <hi>London,</hi> any thing herein before contained to the contrary thereof not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withstanding.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and it is hereby En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted, That it shall and may be Lawful to, and for any Person or Persons, Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives or Foreigners, Bodies Politick or Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porate, to advance and lend unto Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties upon the Security of this Act, any Sum or Sums of Money, and to have and receive for the forbearance thereof, any Sum not exceeding Seven Pounds by the Hundred for one whole year and no more, directly or in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>directly, and that no Money so Lent upon the Security of this Act, shall be Rated or Assessed by Virtue of this Act.</p>
            <p>And to the end that all Moneys which shall be Lent to Their Majesties on the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit of this Act may be well and sufficiently secured out of the Money arising and pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able by this Act, Be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That there shall be provided and kept in Their Majesties Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer (that is to say) in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipts one Book and Register in which all Moneys that shall be paid into the Exchequer, by virtue of this Act, shall be Entred and Registred apart and distinct from all other Moneys paid or payable to Their Majesties upon any other Branch of Their Majesties Revenue, or up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on any other Account whatsoever; And that
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:180540:29"/> all and every Person and Persons who shall Lend any Money to Their Majesties upon the Credit of this Act, and pay the same into the Receipt of the Exchequer, shall immediately have a Tally of Loan struck for the same, and an Order for his or their Repayment, bearing the same Date with his or their Tally; In which Order shall be contained a Warrant for Payment of In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terest for Forbearance thereof, not exceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Seven Pounds <hi>per Centum per Annum</hi> for his or their Consideration, to be paid every Threé Months until repayment of his or their Principal; And that all Orders for repayment of Money shall be Registred in Course, according to the Date of the Tally respectively, without preference of one before another; And that all and every Person and Persons shall be paid in Course, according as their Order shall stand entred in the said Register Book; so as the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons, Natives or Foreigners, his or their Executors, Administrators or Assigns, who shall have his or their Order or Orders first entred in the said Book or Register, shall be taken and accounted the First Person or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons to be paid upon the Moneys to come in by virtue of this Act; And he or they who shall have his or their Order or Orders next entred, shall be taken and accounted to be the Second Person to be paid, and so successively and in Course. And that the Moneys to come in by this Act shall be in the same Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der liable to the Satisfaction of the said re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective Parties, their Executors, Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strators and Assigns respectively and succes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sively,
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:180540:29"/> without preference of one before an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other, and not otherwise, and not to be di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertible to any other Vse, Intent or Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pose whatsoever; And that no Fee, Reward or Gratuity, directly or indirectly, be De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded or Taken of any Their Majesties Subjects, for providing or making of any such Books, Registers, Entries, Views or Search, in or for Payment of Money Lent, or the Interest thereof, as aforesaid, by any of Their Majesties Officer or Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, their Clerks or Deputies, upon pain of paying Treble Damages to the Party a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grieved by the Party offending, with Costs of Suit; Or if the Officer himself take or demand any such Fee or Reward, then to lose his Place also; And if any undue prefe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence of one before another shall be made, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in Point of Registry or Payment, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the true Meaning of this Act, by any such Officer or Officers, then the Party offending shall be liable (by Action of Debt, or on the Case) to pay the Value of the Debt, Damages and Costs to the Party agrieved, and shall be forejudged from his Place or Office; And if such preference be unduly made by any his Deputy or Clerk, without direction or privity of his Master, then such Deputy or Clerk only shall be liable to such Action, Debt, Damages and Costs, and shall be for ever after uncapable of his Place or Office; And in case the Auditor shall not direct the Order, or the Clerk of the Pells Record, or the Teller make Payment accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to each persons due Place and Order, as afore directed, Then he or they shall be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:180540:30"/> to Forfeit, and their respective Depu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties and Clerks herein offending, to be liable to such Action, Debt, Damages and Costs in such manner, as aforesaid; All which said Penalties, Damages, Forfeitures and Costs to be incurred by any of the Officers of the Exchequer, or any their Deputies or Clerks, shall and may be Recovered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint or Information, in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record at <hi>Westminster,</hi> wherein no Essoign, Protection, Priviledge, Wager of Law, Injunction, or Order of Restraint shall be in any wise Granted or Allowed.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it hereby decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, That if it happen that several Tallies of Loan, or Orders for payment, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, bear date, or be brought the same Day to the Auditor of the Receipt to be Registred, Then it shall be interpreted no undue pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ference which of those be entred first, so he enters them all the same day.</p>
            <p>Provided also, that it shall not be Inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preted any undue preference to incur any pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty in point of payment, if the Auditor direct, and the Clerk of the Pells Record, and the Tellers do pay subsequent Orders of persons that come and demand their Monies, and bring their Orders before other persons that did not come to demand their Money, and bring their Order in their course, so as there be so much Money reserved as will sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfie precedent Orders, which shall not be o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwise disposed, but kept for them; Inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>est upon Loan being to cease from the time the Money is so reserved and kept in Bank for them.</p>
            <pb n="59" facs="tcp:180540:30"/>
            <p>And be it further Enacted by the Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty aforesaid, That every Person or Persons to whom any Money shall be due by virtue of this Act, after Order entred in the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ook of Registry aforesaid for payment thereof, his or their Executors, Administrators or As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signs, by Endorsement of his or their Order, may Assign and Transfer his or their Right, Title, Interest and Benefit of such Order, or any part thereof to any other; which being notified in the Office of the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditor of the Receipt aforesaid, and an Entry, or Memorial thereof also made in the Book of Register aforesaid for Orders, which the Officers shall upon Request, without Fee or Charge accordingly make, shall Entitle such Assigneé, his and their Executors, Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nistrators and Assigns, to the benefit there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, and payment thereon, and such Assigneé may in like manner Assign again, and so <hi>toties quoties,</hi> and afterwards it shall not be in the power of such person or persons, who have, or hath made such Assignments, to make Void, Release or Discharge the same, or any the Moneys thereby due, or any part thereof.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it further En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted, That all and every the Principal Sums of Money, not exceéding in the whole the Sum of One hundred and eighteén thousand five hundred and six Pounds Five Shillings and Ten Pence, which in pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suance of an Act lately made, Entituled, <hi>An Act for Granting to Their Majesties certain Rates and Duties of Excise upon Beer, Ale and other Liquors, for securing certain Recompences and
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:180540:31"/> Advantages in the said Act mentioned, to such Persons as shall Voluntarily Advance the Sum of Ten hundred thousand Pounds towards the Carry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing on the War against <hi>France,</hi>
               </hi> and of Their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesties Letters of Privy Seal, bearing Date the Fourteénth Day of <hi>September,</hi> One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand six Hundred ninety threé, made in pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>suance of the said Act, have beén Lent or shall be Lent to Their Majesties, at the Receipt of Exchequer, not having beén repaid; And all and every the Principal Sums of Money, not exceéding in the whole the Sum of Two hundred ninety threé thousand six hundred ninety two Pounds Seventeén Shillings and Ten Pence; which in pursuance of the Act of Parliament lately made, Entituled, <hi>An Act for the Review of the Quarterly Poll,</hi> and of Their Majesties Letters of Privy Seal, bearing Date the Tenth Day of <hi>August,</hi> One thousand six hundred ninety threé, made in pursuance of the said Act, have beén Lent or shall be Lent to Their Majesties at the Receipt of Exchequer, not having been repaid; And all and every the Principal Sums of Money, not exeeeding in the whole the Sum of Four hundred thousand Pounds, which after the Seventeénth Day of <hi>November,</hi> One thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand six hundred ninety threé, have beén Lent or shall be Lent to Their Majesties at the said Receipt, pursuant to Their Majesties Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of Privy Seal, bearing Date the Twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty seventh Day of <hi>November,</hi> One thousand six hundred ninety threé, for or towards Maintenance of Their Majesties Fleét for the Year One thousand six hundred ninety four; And all and every the Orders of Loan
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:180540:31"/> for the said several and respective Principal Sums, shall be in the first place transferred to, and placed upon the Register appointed to be kept by this Act, and shall be Registred thereupon in such Course and Order as the Loans thereof respectively in point of time were made at the said Receipt; Which Transferrences shall and may be, and are hereby required to be made by virtue of this Act, without making any Issues, or taking any Receipts from the Parties in order to transfer the said Loans; And that the Principal Moneys upon the said Orders so transferred, shall be payable and paid to the Lender or Lenders of the same, his, her or their Executors, Administrators or Assigns, out of the Moneys arising by virtue of this Act, in the same Course and Order according to which they are hereby appointed to be transferred, and with preference to the Loans which any Person or Persons shall make hereafter on Credit of this present Act; And that the Interest after the Rate of Seven Pounds <hi>per Centum per Annum</hi> due or to be due for the said Principal Sums, not exceéding One hundred and eighteén thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand five hundred and six Pounds Five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Ten Pence, and Four hundred thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand Pounds, and after the Rate of Eight Pounds <hi>per Cent per Annum</hi> due or to be due for the said Principal Sums, not exceeding Two hundred ninety threé thousand six hundred ninety Two Pounds Seventeen Shillings &amp; Ten Pence to be transferred, as aforesaid, shall be paid and satisfied out of the Moneys arising by this Act, until the respective times
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:180540:32"/> of the satisfaction of the Principal; And that the Auditor of the said Receipt, upon the transferring of the said Loans, or the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders for the same, as aforesaid, shall make <hi>Memorandums</hi> in the Margent of the Books where the same stand entred, importing the transferrence thereof, and that they are to be paid out of the Moneys arising by virtue of this Act; And that any Person or Persons who are or shall be Entituled to any Moneys to be paid by such Orders, to be transferred, as aforesaid, shall or may Assign over the same to any other Person or Persons; Which Assignments shall be good and effectu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al in Law, and so, <hi>toties quoties,</hi> any thing in the said former Acts or in this present Act to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
            <p>And it is hereby further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That out of the Money that hath or shall be Levied or Paid by Virtue of this Act into the Receipt of the Exchequer, as well upon Loans as otherwise, the Sum of Ten hundred thousand Pounds, inclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding therein the Sum of Four hundred thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sand Pounds already Borrowed and to be Borrowed for the Vse of the Navy, as is herein before Declared, shall and is hereby Appropriated for the Services of the Navy and Ordnance, Performed and to be Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed; And that all other Money which shall be Levied and Paid by Virtue of this Act into the Receipt of the Exchequer, as well upon Loans as otherwise, other then the Principal Sums herein before Appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to be transferred to this Act, and the Interest thereof; And also the Sum of Ten
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:180540:32"/> hundred thousand Pounds Appropriated for the Services of the Navy aforesaid, shall be Applied and Appropriated, and is hereby Appropriated, to and for the Payment of Their Majesties Land Forces and Armies, and the Paying for Arms, Ammunition, and other Charges incident to the War, and not otherwise.</p>
            <p>And for the more Effectual doing thereof, and that the Sums by this Act Appropria<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, may not be Diverted or Applied to any other Purpose then is hereby Declared and Intended, Be it Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That the Rules and Directions Appointed and Enacted, in One Act made in the First year of Their Majesties Reign, Entituled, <hi>An Act for a Grant to Their Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sties of an Aid of Two Shillings in the Pound for One year,</hi> for the speedy Payment of Money thereby Granted into the Receipt of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chequer, by the Collectors and Receivers, and for Distribution and Application there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, and keeping distinct Accompts of the same; and all other Provisions, Pains, Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalties and Forfeitures thereby Enacted, in case of Diversion of any Money thereby Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>propriated, are hereby Revived and Enacted to be in Force, and shall be Practised, Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied, Executed and put in Vre, for and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the Distribution and Application of the said Sums hereby Appropriated, as ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, amply and effectually, as if the same were here particularly Repeated and Reenacted.</p>
            <p>And for the better securing the Trade of this Kingdom, Be it further Enacted by the Authority aforesaid, That over and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:180540:33"/> the Ships of War for the Line of Bat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle, and for Convoys to Remote Parts, at the least Four Ships of the Third Rate, Sixteen Ships of the Fourth Rate, Thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teen Ships of the Fifth Rate, and Ten Ships of the Sixth Rate, shall be from time to time Directed and Appointed by the Lord High Admiral of <hi>England,</hi> or Commissioners for Executing the said Office for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, to such proper Stations as they shall deem meet, to Cruize for securing the Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant Ships in their going out and return<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing home.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That nothing in this Act Contained shall Restrain or be Construed to Restrain the Lord High Admiral of <hi>England,</hi> or the Commissioners for Executing the Office of the Lord High Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miral of <hi>England</hi> for the time being, from di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>recting any of the Ships Appointed by this Act to be Cruisers, to be Employed in the Line of Battle in Cases of great Necessity.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it Enacted, That out of the Moneys hereby appropriated to, and for the payment of Officers and Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men that have served, and shall serve in Their Majesties Navy Royal, and to, and for the paying for Naval Stores, other then for Victuals, and Provisions, and to and for the Expences of Their Majesties Office of Ordnance, in respect of Naval Affairs, and for other necessary Vses and Services performed, and to be performed for the said Navy, all such part thereof as shall be Is<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sued and Paid by the Treasurer of the Navy, by Warrant of the Principal Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:180540:33"/> and Commissioners of the Navy, or any Threé or more of them for Naval Stores and Provisions, shall be paid in Course to every Person or Persons, or the Assigns to whom any such Money is, or shall be due, according to the Dates of the Bills or Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracts Registred for the same, and not other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise; And that out of all such further part of the said Moneys as shall be Issued and Paid to the Lieutenant and Principal Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers of the Ordnance, or the Paymaster thereof, or his Deputy, for the Expence of Their Majesties Ordnance, as to Naval Affairs, and by them, or the said Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>master respectively, to any Person or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons, for Ammunition, or any other Vse or Service relating to the Office of the Ord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, shall be in like manner paid in Course to every Person and Persons, or their As<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>signs respectively, according to the respective Dates of the Bills and Contracts for the same, and not otherwise: And the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptroller of the Navy, and Storekeéper of the Ordnance, are hereby respectively requi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red to keép One or more Book or Books in their respective Offices, wherein all Bills and Contracts, in reference to the Navy, and Office of the Ordnance (for such Bills and Contracts respectively as aforesaid) shall be duly Registred, and all and every such Person or Persons concerned therein, may have recourse thereunto, without paying any Feé or Reward for so doing: And if any Preference of one before another shall be made, either in point of Registry, or Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, contrary to the true meaning of this
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:180540:34"/> Act, either by the said Treasurer of the Navy, or Paymaster of the Ordnance, or Comptroller of the Navy, or Storekeeper of the Ordnance, or any of them, or their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spective Deputies or Clerks, then the Parties offending shall be liable, by Action of Debt, or on the Case, to pay double the value of the Debt, Damages and Costs to the Party grieved; All which said Penalties, Dama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges and Costs to be incurred by the Persons aforesaid, or any of them respectively, shall and may be recovered by the said party grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation, in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record at <hi>Westminster,</hi> wherein no Es<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soign, Protection, Priviledge, Wager of Law, Injunction, or Order of Restraint, shall be in any wise granted or allowed.</p>
            <p>Provided nevertheless, that it shall and may be lawful for the said Lieutenant, and Principal Officers of the Ordnance, and the Officers of the Navy-board, upon any E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mergent or extraordinary occasions, to pay any of the said Money appropriated by this Act to any Person or Persons upon Account, by way of Imprest, any thing herein con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
            <p>Provided also, That it shall not be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strued any preference to incur any Penalty in point of payment in course, as aforesaid, if the said Treasurer of the Navy, or Pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>master of the Ordnance, or their Deputies respectively do pay subsequent Bills of Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons which come and demand their Money, and bring their Warrant or Order in their Course for the same, so as there be so much
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:180540:34"/> Money reserved as will satisfie precedent Bills or Contracts Registred, as aforesaid, which shall not be otherwise disposed of, but kept for them in the said respective Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces.</p>
            <p>And whereas the Receivers General, by this Act appointed by a time limited, as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, to return a true Copy, or Extract of the whole Sum Assessed and Charged within every Hundred, Riding, Lathe, Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentake, Parish, Ward, or Place, Rated or Assessed in pursuance of this Act, together with the Sums Assessed upon Personal E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>states, Offices or Employments, and to transmit the same into Their Majesties Court of Exchequer; And the Kings Remembrancer is also required to Transcribe the Schedules and Duplicates of the said Sums to him returned, in a Parchment Book in Alphabe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tical Order, to be by him transmitted to the Office of the Writer of the Tallies, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly called Auditor of the Receipt of the Exchequer, who is thereupon likewise required to enter the same in a Parch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment Book in the like Alphabetical Order: Be it further Enacted, That if any Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver General, by this Act appointed, shall neglect or refuse to return Duplicates of the Sums Assessed and Charged in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, Riding, Hundred, Lathe, Wapentake, Parish, Ward or Places whereof he is Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver General, within the time hereby li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mited, and to return the same into Their Majesties Exchequer, to the Office of the Kings Remembrancer, then every such Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver General shall forfeit the Sum of Fifty
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:180540:35"/> Pounds to any that will Sue for the same, and be thence forth incapable of any Office or Place of Trust in Their Majesties Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice; And if the Kings Remembrancer for the time being, shall neglect or refuse, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the times hereby appointed, to transcribe the Schedules and Duplicates of the Sums to him so returned, in a Book of Parch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in Alphabetical Order, as hereby required, and transmit the same to the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice of the said Writer of the Tallys; And if the said Writer of the Tallys, commonly called Auditor of the Receipt, shall not en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the same in Alphabetical Order in ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Parchment Book, as hereby direct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, they and every of them respectively Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fending, shall forfeit the Sum of One hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pounds to any that will Sue for the same, and be thenceforth incapable of any Office or Place of Trust in Their Majesties Service; Which said Forfeitures by any Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiver General, Kings Remembrancer or Auditor of the Receipt, shall be recovered by Action of Debt, Plaint or Information, in any of Their Majesties Courts of Record at <hi>Westminster;</hi> Wherein no Essoign, Protection, or Wager of Law shall be allowed, nor any more then One Imparlance.</p>
            <p>Provided also, and be it Enacted, That all and every Auditor, Reeve, Receiver, and their Deputies, who receive any Fee-Farm-Rents or other Chief Rents due to Their Majesties or the Queén Dowager, or to any other Person or Persons claiming by any Grant or Purchase, from or under the Crown, shall allow Four Shillings in the
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:180540:35"/> Pound, according to the true intent and meaning of this Act, to the Party and Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties so paying the same, without any Fee for such allowance, upon the Penalty of for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiting the Sum of Ten Pounds, and losing their respective Places and Offices, if they fail therein.</p>
            <p>Provided nevertheless, and it is hereby further Enacted, That nothing in this Act contained shall extend to Charge or Tax any Rector or Vicar who has the Cure of Souls and actually resides upon his Rectory or Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caridge (upon the Account of such his Rectory or Vicaridge only) unless his Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctory or Vicaridge does really and truly ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed the Value of Thirty Pounds by the Year, or unless he has more then One Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctory or Vicaridge.</p>
            <p>Provided always, and be it further Enact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Authority aforesaid, That every Master and Fellow of every College and Hall (who are now resident in this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom and) every Reader and Officer and Minister of either of the Vniversities, shall Voluntarily appear before the said Commissi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners, or any Three or more of them, before the time limited for Returning the Assess<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments to be made by virtue of this Act be Expired, and take the Oaths required and mentioned to be taken by an Act made in the First Year of Their Majesties Reign, En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tituled, <hi>An Act for the Abrogating the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and Appointing other Oaths;</hi> which Oaths the said Commissioners are hereby impowered and required to Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minister, and make an Entry and <hi>Memo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>randum</hi>
               <pb n="70" facs="tcp:180540:36"/> thereof in some Book to be kept for that purpose, and upon neglect or not ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearing and taking the said Oaths, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said, Eight Shillings in the Pound of the Profeits which he or they might have re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived, had he or they taken the said Oaths, for or by reason of all and every Stipend, Wages, Salary or Profits whatsoever a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rising or growing due, in respect of the said several Places or Imployments in the said Vniversities, Colleges or Halls, shall be actually paid to Their Majesties for the Vse of the War, and be Levied, Collected and Received in such manner, as the rest of the Money Given by this Act.</p>
            <p>Provided always, that nothing herein contained shall extend, or be construed to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tend to confirm any of the said Persons who have, or shall neglect, or refuse to take the said Oaths in such manner as is herein be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore appointed in their respective Places and Employments.</p>
            <p>Provided always, That nothing contain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in this Act shall be construed or taken to Discharge any Tenant, of any the Houses or Lands belonging to the said Colleges, Halls, Hospitals, Almshouses, or Schools, or any of them, who by their Leases or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Contracts are, and do stand obliged to Pay, and Discharge all Rates, Taxes and Impositions whatsoever: But that they and every of them shall be Rated, and Pay all such Rates, Taxes and Impositions, any thing in this Act contained to the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary notwithstanding.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>